<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">

    <string name="titles0">%1$s; menstrual cycle length %2$d days; luteal phase length %3$d days</string>
    <string name="titles1">%1$s</string>
    <string name="titles2_gestational">on %1$s determined gestational age of %2$s</string>
    <string name="titles2_emryonic">on %1$s determined fertilization age of %2$s</string>
    <string name="titles3">on %1$s determined gestational age of %2$s</string>
    <string name="titles4_first_pregnancy">%1$s; first pregnancy</string>
    <string name="titles4_second_pregnancy">%1$s; second pregnancy</string>

    <string-array name="methodNames">
        <item>by last menstrual period</item>
        <item>by ovulation (conception) date</item>
        <item>by ultrasound</item>
        <item>by clinical examination</item>
        <item>by first fetal movement</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="MethodNames">
        <item>By last menstrual period</item>
        <item>By ovulation (conception) date</item>
        <item>By ultrasound</item>
        <item>By clinical examination</item>
        <item>By first fetal movement</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="helpTitles">
        <item>Accuracy of methods</item>
        <item>By last menstrual period</item>
        <item>By ovulation (conception) date</item>
        <item>By ultrasound</item>
        <item>By clinical examination</item>
        <item>By first fetal movement</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="helpParts">
        <item>
<![CDATA[
<b><i>EDD</i></b> &mdash; estimated date of delivery.<br/><br/>

Actual day of delivery <b><i>can vary from EDD by two weeks</b></i>.<br/><br/>

Pregnancy lengths <b><i>between 38 and 42 weeks</i></b> are considered normal.<br/><br/>

Calculation methods <b><i>by last menstrual period</i></b> and <b><i>by ovulation (conception) date</i></b> give more
 accurate values for women with regular menses.<br/><br/>

If you use some methods to determine ovulation date, and know
 on which day of your cycle an ovulation occurs, then EDD will be calculated with high accuracy.<br/><br/>

But many factors (physical and emotional,
 stresses, illness, etc.)
 may affect on the cycle length and the day when ovulation occurs
 (the most fertile day).<br/><br/>

If you have had single sexual intercourse after which you have got pregnant, then you can use the date of
 this sexual intercourse as an expected conception date. But you should keep in mind
 that conception may occur in few days after sexual intercourse.<br/><br/>

Calculation method by ovulation (conception) date gives high accuracy for women who get pregnant with
 In Vitro Fertilization (IVF)
 and know the date of artificial insemination exactly.<br/><br/>

Calculation method <b><i>by ultrasound</i></b> is the most accurate.
 An ultrasound done between 9 and 13 weeks gives error in 1-3 days,
 because there is very little variation in fetal size in the first trimester.
 Ultrasound in late pregnancy is not so reliable.<br/><br/>

Calculation method <b><i>by clinical examination</i></b> gives low accuracy.
 EDD can be calculated with error in few weeks.
 The doctor overseeing pregnancy may determine the gestational age and EDD suggesting
 on the size and position of the uterus and other features.
 The sooner a woman visit the doctor (preferably up to 12 weeks), the more accurate will be determined
 gestational age.<br/><br/>

Calculation method <b><i>by first fetal movement</i></b> gives very low accuracy.
 Feeling of fetal movement depends on the individual characteristics of the woman.
 The period when the woman feels the first fetal movement can vary from 16 to 25 weeks.<br/><br/>
]]>
        </item>
        <item>
<![CDATA[
<b>MC</b> &mdash; menstrual cycle; <b>LP</b> &mdash; luteal phase (the second phase of MC);
 <b>FP</b> &mdash; follicular phase (the first phase of MC).<br/><br/>

Leave the default values for the length of MC or LF, if you can not specify them.<br/><br/>

If menses are irregular, then use average length of
 last three cycles as MC length.<br/><br/>

The average <i>length of MC</i> lasts 28 days and varies
 from 21 to 35 days.<br/><br/>

The average <i>length of LP</i> lasts 14 days and varies
 from 10 to 16 days.<br/><br/>

While luteal phase length varies significantly from woman to woman,
 for the same woman the length will be fairly consistent from cycle to cycle.
 To get the most probable day of ovulation you should subtract LP length from MC length.
 (For example, if you have cycle that lasts 35 days, LP that lasts 16 days, then ovulation occurs on 19th day of cycle).<br/><br/>

<i><b>Refined EDD</b> = Last menstrual period + FP length + 38 weeks,</i><br/><br/>

where <i>FP length = MC length - LP length,</i><br/><br/>

<i>Last menstrual period</i> is the first day of last menstruation.<br/><br/>

The application calculates refined EDD, since it is more accurate than gestational EDD.
 If you leave default value of MC and LP,
 then you get value of gestaional EDD calculated by the formula:
 <i><b>Gestational EDD</b> = Last menstrual period + 40 weeks.</i><br/><br/>

<b><i>Attention:</i></b> if lengths of MC and LP do not coincide with the average (28 and 14 days
 respectively), the EDD may fall for pregnancy length other than 40 weeks.<br/><br/>

<i><b>Gestational age</b> = Specified date - Last menstrual period.</i><br/><br/>
]]>
        </item>
        <item>
<![CDATA[
<i><b>EDD by ovulation (conception)</b> = Ovulation (conception) date + 38 weeks,</i><br/><br/>

where <i>Ovulation (conception) date</i> is expected date of ovulation, intercourse, or artifical insemination.<br/><br/>

<b><i>Attention:</i></b> pregnancy length is considered to be 38 weeks in this case,
 and EDD will correspond with pregnancy length in 38 weeks.<br/><br/>

<i><b>Fertilization age</b> = Specified date - Ovulation (conception) date.</i><br/><br/>
]]>
        </item>
        <item>
<![CDATA[
<i><b>EDD</b> = Ultrasound date + Expected pregnancy length -
 Determined gestational (fertilization) age.</i><br/><br/>

Expected pregnancy length is considered to be 40 weeks, if you select "Gestational age",
 or 38 weeks, if you select "Fertilization age" (counted from ovulation, intercourse, or artificial insemination day).
 As a rule, if an ultrasound determines the embryo or fetus, the conclusion indicates "Gestational age",
 if only the fertilized egg, the "Fertilization age".
 Consult your doctor about it.<br/><br/>

<b><i>Attention:</i></b> pregnancy length is considered to be 40 weeks, if gestational age is specified,
 or 38 weeks, if fertilization age is specified.<br/><br/>

<i><b>Gestational (fertilization) age</b> = Specified date - Starting point of pregnancy,</i><br/><br/>

where <i>Starting point of pregnancy = Ultrasound date - Determined gestational (fertilization) age.</i><br/><br/>
]]>
        </item>
        <item>
<![CDATA[
<i><b>EDD</b> = Date of examination - Determined gestational age + 40 weeks.</i><br/><br/>

Expected pregnancy length is considered to be 40 weeks.<br/><br/>

<i><b>Gestational age</b> = Specified date - Starting point of pregnancy,</i><br/><br/>

where <i>Starting point of pregnancy = Date of examination - Determined gestational age.</i><br/><br/>
]]>
        </item>
        <item>
<![CDATA[
If it is first pregnancy, <i><b>EDD</b> = First fetal movement date + 20 weeks.</i><br/><br/>

If it is second pregnancy, <i><b>EDD</b> = First fetal movement date + 22 weeks.</i><br/><br/>

Expected pregnancy length is considered to be 40 weeks.<br/><br/>

<i><b>Gestational age</b> = Specified date - Starting point of pregnancy,</i><br/><br/>

where <i>Starting point of pregnancy = First fetal movement date - 20 weeks (for first pregnancy)
 or 18 weeks (for second pregnancy).</i><br/><br/>
]]>
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>